pega.com 2015-06-30

# Pega | Privacy and Security

This Privacy Statement describes the ways in which Pegasystems Inc. (“Pegasystems,” “we,” “our,” or “us”) may collect, use, and disclose information about you through the Pega websites, applications, and other online services that link to this statement (collectively, the “Online Services”), and the choices you can make about the way your information is collected through the Online Services. By using the Online Services, you consent to the processing of your information as set forth in this Privacy Statement, now and as amended by us.

**What information do we collect?**

Information You Provide – We and our service providers collect any information that you provide when you use the Online Services, including when you create an account; participate in our message boards and discussion forums or otherwise contribute content to the Online Services; apply for a job; make a purchase (e.g., purchase credits for use at Pega Academy); participate in polls and surveys; register for events and self-study courses; sign up to receive electronic newsletters and other materials; download or request software, product upgrades, reports, and other information; or contact us with a question, comment, or request, including requests for technical support.

The information that you provide us can include, but is not limited to, your name, your photograph and contact information such as your physical address, email address and phone number; username, password, and other registration information; transaction-related information; information you provide when submitting an employment application; information you provide when you make a request or otherwise contact us; and any other information you choose to make public on the Online Services (e.g., information shared with other users on Pega Mesh, the Pega Discovery Network and other online communities).

When you make a purchase using a credit card on the Online Services, your credit card information is transmitted directly to our third-party payment processor. Pegasystems does not store your credit card information and the third-party payment processor does not share your credit card information with us.

Information About You – When you use the Online Services, such as for training courses on Pega Academy, we will collect and store information about your use of these services, including courses you have registered for, courses you have completed, and certifications that you have received.

Information Automatically Collected From You – We and our service providers may automatically collect certain technical information from your computer or mobile device over time and across different websites when you use the Online Services, such as your Internet Protocol address, your browser type, your operating system, the pages you view on the Online Services, the pages you view immediately before and after you access the Online Services, and the search terms you enter on the Online Services. This information allows us to recognize you and personalize your experience if you return to the Online Services, to improve the Online Services and the products and services we provide, and to provide you with advertisements targeted to your interests (commonly referred to as “Targeted Advertisements”). We and our service providers may collect and store this information using “cookies,” which are small text files that many websites save on your computer when you visit and access when you return, or similar technologies.

Precise Real-Time Location Information – Our mobile applications may collect precise information about the location of your mobile device, but only with your express consent. Once you have consented to the collection of the precise location of your mobile device, you may adjust this consent by managing your location services preferences through the settings of your mobile device.

**How do we use this information?**

We, and our affiliates and subsidiaries, may use the information we collect for a number of purposes, including, but not limited to, providing you with the products, services, or information you request; supporting your customer or partner relationship with us (e.g., notifying you of a product update); processing any transactions you have authorized; processing an employment application; verifying your identity; providing you with information about the Online Services or required notices; delivering Targeted Advertisements and other marketing communications, promotional materials, or advertisements that may be of interest to you (e.g., if you view a webpage about a particular product or service, we or a service provider of ours may later display an advertisement for a related product or service on a different webpage that you visit through the Online Services or on another website that has a relationship with the service provider); allowing us to improve the Online Services and the products and services we provide, such as by better tailoring our content to our users’ needs and interests; generating and analyzing statistics about your use of the Online Services; and detecting, preventing, and responding to fraud, intellectual property infringement, violations of our Terms of Use, violations of law, or other misuse of the Online Services.

We also may combine or aggregate any of the information we collect through the Online Services or elsewhere (e.g., through telephone, email, or personal contact with us or our employees, product registration, call centers, or public events such as trade shows or seminars) for any of these purposes.

**Under what circumstances do we disclose this information?**

We may disclose the information we collect from you through the Online Services to our affiliates and subsidiaries; to service providers and suppliers who work on our behalf and who have agreed to keep the information confidential and use the information solely to carry out the services that they are performing for us; to other users of our Online Services, consistent with your privacy settings; as required by law, such as to comply with a subpoena or other legal process, a court order, or government reporting obligations; when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary (a) to protect our rights, the integrity of the Online Services, or your safety or the safety of others, or (b) to detect, prevent, or respond to fraud, intellectual property infringement, violations of our Terms of Use, violations of law, or other misuse of the Online Services; and to service providers, advisors, and other third parties to the extent reasonably necessary to proceed with the negotiation or completion of a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of our assets.

In addition, we may share de-identified information, such as reports on user demographics and traffic patterns, with third parties.

We will not sell, rent, or lease information that can personally identify you to others except as described in this Privacy Statement.

The Online Services also may contain links to third-party websites and applications for your convenience and information. Pega does not control those third-party websites and applications or their privacy practices, which may differ from ours. You acknowledge and agree that we are not responsible for the collection and use of your information by third-party websites and applications that are not under our control, and such information is not governed by this Privacy Statement.

**Where is this information processed?**

Information collected through the Online Services will be processed in and subject to the laws of the United States. In addition, we may transfer your information outside the United States to our affiliates, subsidiaries, and service providers located in other countries for purposes that include data consolidation, storage, and simplified customer information management. By using the Online Services, you consent to such transfer to, and processing in, the United States and these other countries.

Pegasystems has certified its compliance with the U.S.-EU and U.S.-Switzerland Safe Harbor Frameworks with respect to certain personal data that is transferred from countries in the EU or Switzerland to Pegasystems in the U.S. Please click here to review Pegasystems’ Safe Harbor Policy.

**How is your information secured?**

We strive to maintain reasonable administrative, technical, and physical safeguards designed to safeguard the information collected by the Online Services. However, no information system can be 100% secure, so we cannot guarantee the absolute security of your information. Moreover, we are not responsible for the security of information you transmit to the Online Services over networks that we do not control, including the Internet and wireless networks.

**Your choices**

You have the ability to access your account and modify your account information online.

If you do not want the Online Services to collect information through the use of cookies, you can set your web browser to reject cookies from the Online Services. Each browser is different, so you should check your browser’s “Help” menu to learn how to change your cookie preferences. If you reject or block cookies from the Online Services, however, the Online Services may not function as intended.

**Children’s information**

The Online Services are not directed to, nor do we knowingly collect information from, children under the age of 13. If you become aware that your child or any child under your care has provided us with information without your consent, please contact us at the contact information listed below.

**Changes to this Privacy Statement**

If we update this Privacy Statement, we will notify you by posting a new Privacy Statement on this page and updating the revision date below. If we make any revisions that materially change the ways in which we use or disclose the information previously collected from you through the Online Services, we will give you the opportunity to consent to such changes before applying them to that previously collected information.

**Contact us**

If you have any questions about this Privacy Statement or our use of your information collected through the Online Services, please contact us.
